Imperial Diary.
Year 10. 191. third comment.
The battle for Arrakis
took everyone by surprise.
There were no witnesses.
The Harkonnen operation
was perpetrated overnight
without warning
or declaration of war.
By morning.
the Atreides were no more.
All died in the dark.
And the Emperor said...
nothing.
Since that night. my father
has not been the same.
nor have I.
His inaction is difficult
for me to accept.
for. I know he loved
Duke Leto Atreides like a son.
But my father's
always been guided
by the calculus of power.
This would not
be the first time
the Harkonnens have done
his dirty work.
In the shadows of Arrakis
lie many secrets...
but the darkest of them all
may remain.
The end of House Atreides.
Sister.
Father is dead.
Shouldn't you go
back to the stars?
Be with him?
I'm afraid I won't
have enough time
to fix things
before your coming.
This world is beyond cruelty.
Stay here.
Whoa.
Whoa!
Never stand with your back
towards the open.
How many times do I have
to tell you that. huh?
- You okay?
- Yeah.
How 'bout her?
She's fine.
They do not
usually venture this deep.
They want to make sure
no Atreides escaped.
You think
too much of yourself.
No. no.
we are in the deep desert.
Only Fremen can survive here.
They were here for us.
not for you.
Don't worry.
I'm taking you somewhere
they will never find us.
Filthy water.
It's full of chemicals
but good enough
for cooling systems.
Don't let it out.
- You okay?
- Mm-hmm.
Don't let that out.
Don't let it out. No.
I'm okay.
- Are you sure?
- Mm-hmm.
You fought well...
once you woke up.
I wasn't sleeping.
No. no. no. I'll do it.
Lord... Lord Rabban.
Now that the spice fields
have been secured.
I strongly recommend
bringing all troops
out of Fremen territories.
We're losing too many men
to the desert.
Rats.
I beg your pardon?
We're losing men to rats.
Fremen.
I can't confirm. my Lord.
Communications are hectic
in the open sands.
Your orders were to control
the whole planet.
We are.
I see only half of it.
As you may recall.
the South is uninhabitable.
my Lord.
May I suggest
you get some rest?
Rats! Hairy rats! Kill them!
Kill them all! Kill them all!
Rats!
He's asking why we're so late.
- ...Harkonnen.
- No. no.
He thinks you're spies.
He said...
I got that.
Thanks.
Stay close to me.
Hmm?
Sietch Tabr.
Look how
your Bene Gesserit propaganda
has taken root.
Some of them already think
I'm their messiah.
Others...
false prophet.
I must sway the non-believers.
If they follow me.
we can disrupt
spice production.
That's the only way
I can get to the Emperor.
Your father didn't
believe in revenge.
Yeah. well. I do.
What is happening?
Whoa.
What is it?
There is spice
in the food.
Woman.
come with me.
...Jamis.
38.000.000 decaliters.
None of us. even...
dying of thirst.
would ever drink this water.
This is...
sacred.
Jamis' water.
We have a...
thousand such places.
When we have enough water.
the Lisan al-Gaib
will change
the face of Arrakis.
He will bring back the trees.
He will bring back...
the Green Paradise.
So many souls.
Hmm.
Never give your water away.
not even for the dead. Hmm?
Why are you showing me this?
Because you are Bene Gesserit.
Because you understand
the prophecies.
The mother
of the Lisan al-Gaib
will be a Reverend Mother.
Our Reverend Mother is dying.
You want me to take her place?
Yes.
I do.
You believe in Paul?
There are signs. yes.
What if I would refuse?
Mm. Then.
he's not Lisan al-Gaib
and you have
no purpose to serve.
What else is left to do then
but to return your water
to the well?
Huh?
It's an honor. isn't it?
I think you should
feel honored.
Well. it was a choice
between this or death.
so. you know. forgive me
if I'm not flattered.
How does one become
a Reverend Mother?
It's different
from one culture to another.
Here on Arrakis.
I have no idea.
You're afraid.
Reverend Mothers are tasked
with holding the memories
of all the Reverend Mothers
that came before them.
so I'll be given centuries
of pain and sorrow.
Is it dangerous?
It's lethal for men.
That's for sure.
What are you guys
laughing about?
Don't bother.
You don't believe in all this?
No. we don't.
These are
old Southern beliefs.
Southern beliefs?
Southern tribes believe
a messiah will come
to deliver us from evil.
You don't believe
in the Lisan al-Gaib?
We believe in Fremen.
- Bi-lal kaifa.
You want to control people.
you tell them
a messiah will come.
Then they'll wait
for centuries.
Now. we must pray.
What about him?
- Stilgar?
- Mm-hmm.
He's from the South.
You didn't notice his accent?
What'll happen to my mother?
I must not fear.
Fear is the mind-killer.
Fear. the little death
that brings
total obliteration.
I will face my fear. I will...
- What is it?
- Drink!
She's right.
She's right!
It's no miracle.
My mother was trained
to do that.
Poison transmutation
is something
advanced Bene Gesserit can do.
I'm not the Mahdi.
I'm not here to lead.
Let me fight beside you.
That's all I'm asking.
How are you?
Better.
How is she?
She was
frightened but she's...
she's okay.
Paul...
she talks to me.
She believes in you.
She says...
You're so close now.
Only one step remains
and you will become
the Kwisatz Haderach.
Only one step remains.
You must do what I did.
You must drink
the Water of Life.
Free your mind. it's gonna...
it's gonna open
and you will see.
If you wanna fight with us.
first thing. you must learn
to be one with the desert.
So. here is a tent
and enough food.
I want you to cross
that small erg and come back.
Travel by night.
You know how
to use a paracompass?
- Yes.
- Oh.
Anything else I should know?
Uh. beside the worms
and the Harkonnens.
beware of
the trapdoor spiders.
Centipedes are very nasty.
Not the big ones.
They are harmless.
But the little ones
you have to worry about.
and... Oh!
Don't ever.
ever listen to the jinn.
- The jinn?
- Jinn.
Desert spirits.
They whisper at night.
They. they can possess you.
Really. be careful.
They are demons.
But it's true.
Don't listen to them.
Huh?
Jamis.
You sandwalk
like a drunk lizard.
Yeah. I'm doing
pretty good so far.
Yeah. well. you're not even
in worm territory yet.
You have to break up
your rhythm.
Like this.
Now. that's interesting
because in the filmbooks
I've studied.
the anthropologists say.
in order to properly sandwalk.
you actually have to...
Never mind.
Please keep going.
You know.
I'm the only one who believes
you're gonna make it
until summer.
Everyone else thinks
you won't make it two weeks.
If you wanna follow us
in the desert.
you need to know
how windtraps work.
So listen to me.
They're simple. but they
require constant attention.
Uh...
This right here.
it captures the moisture
and then it carries it
into that pocket.
Uh. and...
These are the filters
that need to be changed
every three days.
What?
Stop looking at me like that.
He's training with the Fremen.
He will be back soon.
Don't worry.
Mm-hmm.
You're right.
If we want to protect
your brother.
we need all the Fremen
to believe in the prophecy.
We must convert
the non-believers one by one.
We need to start
with the weaker ones.
The vulnerable ones.
The ones who fear us.
Hey. get out of here. Go.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Let's go! Move!
Load!
Chani!
Reload!
Watch out!
Its shield will only open
when it fires.
I know that. What do
you think I'm trying to do?
I'll trigger it.
On my signal. Be ready.
Go!
Oh. shit!
Go. go!
Mm.
Who taught you
to fight like that?
- My old masters.
- Hmm.
And they were close friends.
They were massacred.
Alongside my father.
You've been fighting
the Harkonnens for decades.
My family's been fighting them
for centuries.
I know everything about them.
Their habits.
their ways of thinking.
You know everything
about the desert.
You harness
the very power of it.
We can stop them together.
Bury them in the sand
where they belong.
So that this planet
can be yours once more.
What will you have us do? Huh?
- What would you do. Stilgar?
- I? I would...
...would strike
even further north.
Then I will go further north.
And the further north you go.
the more likely it is you die.
I see strength in you.
Come. Come.
You
shall be known among us
as Usul.
Usul.
- Usul.
And now.
a Fedaykin is a fighter
and needs a war name.
You must choose.
How do you call the. uh...
the small desert mouse. again?
- Muad'Dib.
No. no. no. Shh.
Muad'Dib is wise
in the ways of the desert.
Muad'Dib...
creates his own water.
The constellation that points
to the North Star
we call Muad'Dib.
"The One Who Points the Way."
That is a powerful name.
Now you are our brother. Hmm.
Paul Muad'Dib Usul.
Muad'Dib Usul.
Muad'Dib.
- Usul.
- Muad'Dib.
Muad'Dib.
Hey!
Stilgar!
Father. I found my way.
It's breathtaking.
Hmm.
Look. Right there. Spice.
Arrakis is so beautiful
when the sun is low.
Where you're from.
does water really fall
from the sky?
Oh. yes.
Sometimes it rains for weeks
on Caladan.
Where you see sand here.
imagine water.
Our castle stands on cliffs
high above the sea.
If you dive in.
you can't reach the bottom.
- You dive in?
- Yes.
it's called swimming.
I don't...
I don't believe you. Usul.
Usul.
What's your secret name?
Sihaya.
- Sihaya.
- Mm.
What does that mean?
Means "Desert Spring."
"Desert Spring."
- I love it.
- I hate it.
It's from some
stupid prophecy.
I prefer Chani.
I prefer Chani too then.
Do you think Stilgar
would teach me?
- To ride?
- Yeah.
No. Only Fremen ride worms.
Well. I thought
I'd become one. didn't I?
By name. not by blood.
Your blood comes from Dukes
and Great Houses.
We don't have that here.
Here.
we're equal.
men and women alike.
What we do.
we do for the benefit of all.
Well. I'd very much
like to be equal to you.
Paul Muad'Dib Usul.
maybe you could be Fremen.
Maybe I'll show you the way.
Rabban.
Fremen attacks on your watch.
Your orders were to restore
spice production
to full capacity.
Do you know
what it means if you fail?
The Emperor would take spice
out of our control.
Tighten your grip. Rabban.
Uncle.
Or feel mine on your neck.
Usul. Usul. It's okay.
It's okay.
Hey.
I'm here. I'm here.
It's been a while since you've
had one of those nightmares.
Mm.
Tell me. what was it about?
Nothing's clear.
It's only fragments.
I'm in the south.
And I'm following someone.
And it triggers a holy war.
Millions and millions
of people
starving to death...
because of me.
You've been exposed
to spice for a long time.
It can create weird dreams.
It's a big day.
We can ask Stilgar
to call it off.
No.
I'm fine.
Usul.
I tuned it myself.
- Here.
- Thanks.
Don't try to impress anyone.
You are brave.
We all know that. Heh?
Be simple.
Be direct.
- Nothing fancy.
Hey. I'm serious.
Nothing fancy
or you will shame my teaching.
I won't shame you.
I understand.
Shai-Hulud decides today
if you become Fremen.
or if you die.
Hey. Muad'Dib...
Lower.
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
okay. okay.
Okay. okay!
Come on!
Whoa!
Go. Muad'Dib!
Muad'Dib!
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
I know they do.
Our task in the North
is nearly done.
They believe in Paul.
Now we go South.
There are millions
of fundamentalists there.
They will protect him
when he comes.
The Kwisatz Haderach
will be born in the South.
As long as I breathe.
What's wrong?
Chani.
There will be trouble.
What are you talking about?
Chani. what do you mean?
The way they look at you.
They worship you now.
The Fedaykin.
they count your victories.
They say
you can see the future.
Whisper Lisan al-Gaib.
I'm no messiah.
I'm a Fedaykin of Sietch Tabr.
Yet. we have a Bene Gesserit
among us.
fanning the flames
of your legend.
saying you're the One.
Mm.
She says
you should be coming with us.
You know I can't.
She's asking why.
Because I must continue
fighting in the North
to protect you down there
in the South.
She says she can tell
when you lie.
Tell her that's because
our mother keeps spreading
dangerous tales.
What is she saying now?
She says
you're blinded by love.
And she reminds you that
you must reserve your hand
for the most strategic alliance.
She's also wondering
why you don't believe
in who you are.
I do believe.
I believe I matter
to these people.
I believe I'm making
a difference in this war.
We're nearly
at the gates of the city.
That's not what she means.
I know what she means.
Do you not think I also feel
the weight of the prophecy?
It's not a prophecy.
It's a story
that you keep telling.
but it's not their story.
it's yours.
They deserve to be led
by one of their own.
What your people
did to this world
is heartbreaking.
We gave them something
to hope for.
That's not hope!
I'll be waiting for you.
All of us.
Those storms look bad.
How much?
We lost eighty
percent of our last crop.
My Lord Rabban.
you should not leave
the security perimeter.
Security perimeter?
The rats are already inside!
The Fremen Demon
might be with them.
- I hope so.
- We're tracking them. my Lord.
Today. Muad'Dib dies!
Where is he?
Still negative. my Lord.
Why do I have
to do everything myself?
- Open range!
- Range open.
Life. Delta. delta. delta.
I've lost them.
- Strike!
- Yes. my Lord.
Muad'Dib!
Show yourself!
Muad'Dib! Muad'Dib! Muad'Dib!
For Muad'Dib!
Muad'Dib.
Some new Fremen prophet.
It's not the first time
we've had frictions
with the Fremen.
None of this magnitude.
So. my dear daughter.
how would you deal
with this prophet?
If this Muad'Dib
is a religious figure.
you can't use direct force.
Repression only makes
a religion flourish.
You'll only end up
humiliating yourself.
You underestimate
my Sardaukar.
the power of faith.
Her Highness proves once again
that she was
my most acute student.
- You'd send assassins?
- No.
Prophets get stronger
when they die.
Let the conflict on Arrakis
turn into war.
You then bring peace.
As a savior.
You'd be a formidable empress.
Muad'Dib.
The prophet.
The one who points the way.
These are
our own religious patterns.
aren't they?
This is our doing.
Muad'Dib means kangaroo mouse.
an unusual war name
for a Fremen.
What if Paul Atreides
were still alive?
Enough!
This must not come out.
Even to your father's ears.
Understand?
I do. Reverend Mother.
If Paul is alive.
he likely knows the truth.
And should
the Great Houses learn
that your father was behind
the liquidation
of the Atreides.
your father will face war
and lose the throne.
Then what hope is there?
Hope?
We are Bene Gesserit.
We don't hope. we plan.
Paul is not our only prospect.
The Baron's youngest nephew.
Feyd-Rautha Harkonnen.
will inherit Arrakis.
He may be the answer.
Feyd-Rautha? He's psychotic.
That's irrelevant.
The question is.
can we control him?
And I intend to find out.
Would you like
some fresh meat. my darlings?
Lungs? Or liver?
What would you like?
I hear they're big today.
Your new blades
for this very special day.
na-Baron. Feyd-Rautha.
A notch off balance.
It's the tip.
Should be sharper.
Come.
I won't die
like a fool.
Kill me now.
No drug for you today.
Atreides.
Welcome
to Giedi Prime. sisters.
I hope your travels
were agreeable.
A long way to come
just to watch our prospect
risk his life.
Lady Fenring.
No fear.
These fights are all for show.
But we'll get
a good look at him.
Feyd-Rautha!
That slave isn't drugged.
That bug is walking straight.
We should cancel the fight.
Don't spoil
my nephew's birthday.
Happy birthday. dear nephew.
Why do
they not stop the fight?
Plans within plans.
Show me who you are.
There he is.
Back! Back!
Stay back!
You fought well. Atreides.
Feyd-Rautha!
Feyd-Rautha! Feyd-Rautha!
He's impressive. indeed.
Feyd-Rautha!
Feyd-Rautha! Feyd-Rautha!
The slave wasn't drugged.
You tried to kill me?
This morning
you were a playboy.
feared and envied.
but tonight you're a hero.
My gift to you.
I ought to drown you
in that tub.
Don't be hasty.
I have another gift for you.
A bigger one.
Arrakis.
What about Rabban?
He has failed to protect
spice production.
Rabban will be reassigned.
Tame Arrakis. Feyd.
Free the spice.
I'll make you emperor.
Emperor?
How?
The Emperor helped me
destroy the Atreides.
He lent his own army
to the cause.
A serious crime.
If it came to light.
the Great Houses
would rise against him.
And then.
who will sit on the throne?
Feyd-Rautha Harkonnen.
You're following me.
Am I?
I may have gotten lost.
Will you show me the way
out of this maze.
my Lord na-Baron?
We've met. haven't we?
I don't think so.
I'm Lady Margot Fenring.
I'm here to honor
your coming of age.
You're not allowed
in this section.
How did you
get past the guards?
The guards?
May I ask.
what are you doing here?
You're not taking part
in your own celebrations?
You're Bene Gesserit.
And what makes you say that?
I remember now.
I dreamed about you
last night.
A pleasant dream. I hope.
Don't mock me. woman.
I wouldn't dare.
I know your
Bene Gesserit tricks.
And what do you know
about the Bene Gesserit?
Tell me.
Something wrong?
I don't recognize this place.
This is the guest wing.
Where are you going?
To my room.
Come...
To...
Me.
Kneel.
Put your right hand
in the box.
A sociopath.
Of high intelligence.
Driven. Cruel.
But strongly motivated
by honor.
He yearns to be hurt.
He loves pain.
Can he be redeemed?
He can be controlled.
He's sexually vulnerable.
And?
The bloodline is secured.
Female. as you requested.
You did well. Margot.
Respectfully. why didn't you
test him yourself?
I'm a motherly figure.
And based on what happened
between him
and his own mother.
I didn't expect
to be effective.
What happened between
him and his mother?
He murdered her.
Desire and humiliation.
Those are his levers.
If Feyd-Rautha prevails
on Arrakis.
we shall know
how to control him.
Rid me of this Fremen Demon.
Feyd-Rautha!
Feyd-Rautha! Feyd-Rautha!
Do away with these idiots I blame
The stillsuit is full of piss
My hand is caked in sand
Save me from these utter morons
Another world
Another land
We're in.
Juicy?
Juicy. juicy.
Well.
it was nice knowing ya.
Oh. yeah?
Radar's clear. We're clear.
Cooking time.
Juicy. juicy.
Yeah.
I got a meter reading...
All right. guys.
worms are on their way.
Watch out
for abrasions.
Get ready to dock.
It's gonna get hot
when we get started.
All right. move it!
- Crank them up!
- Start them up!
Yeah.
I'm moving. I'm moving.
Hold!
Mine! Mine!
Get moving!
Come on!
East! East!
Get clear!
Let's get outta here.
Incoming!
Don't run. fight!
We're in deep Fremen shit.
Holy Mother.
- Go. go. go now!
- Fuck. fuck!
Get out!
We gotta run!
What the heck.
let's go!
I recognized
your footsteps.
old man.
You young pup.
Ah!
Well. after
the Battle of Arrakeen.
I was able to negotiate
a trip back home
for the survivors.
Thanks to these guys.
Why'd you stay?
I wanted blood.
Rabban's head?
Mm-hmm.
Since Muad'Dib
has been driving Rabban crazy.
the smuggling business
has been quite profitable.
Gurney Halleck the smuggler.
Paul Muad'Dib.
I've heard many stories
about Muad'Dib.
None of them pretty.
You see the fear?
When our resources
are limited.
fear is all we have.
How many men with you?
- Two Hundred.
- Two Hundred?
Shh!
Do you realize what you're
able to achieve with 200 men?
Incredible fighters.
Duncan said
there were millions of them.
In the Deep South. yes.
Well.
what are you waiting for?
With thousands of these guys.
you could take control
of the entire planet.
It's your father's dream.
- What are you afraid of?
- Hey.
Worship. Gurney.
They used to be friends.
Now they're followers.
Muad'Dib. the Prophet.
Why is that a bad thing?
Use it.
It's not that simple.
You have the power
to avenge your father.
and you're afraid to use it?
Spice opened my mind. Gurney.
I can foresee things.
If I go South.
all my visions lead to horror.
Billions of corpses
scattered across the galaxy.
All dying because of me.
Because you lose control?
Because I gain it.
That's a lot of water.
Chani.
What?
Look at him. he's hopeless.
He's family.
Really?
No need to be a prophet
to see what's ahead.
Your path leads to war.
You know that.
So. war is coming.
What will you do
when you feel its breath
upon your neck?
If you don't want
to raise an army in the South.
you may still have an option.
Firepower.
which you don't have.
And here I am.
I know where your father
hid the family atomics.
Every House possesses
an atomic arsenal.
I thought ours had been lost.
It's huge. Chani.
It could change everything.
I could aim the bombs
at the main spice fields.
He who can destroy a thing
has the real control of it.
So. you can control it
and not us?
You promised me
you didn't want power.
No matter what I do.
you still don't trust me.
'Cause you're a foreigner.
Like your friend.
I'm not a foreigner.
Not to me.
But to the desert. you are.
My allegiance is to you.
To the Fremen.
I'm doing this for all of us.
Do you believe me?
I'll talk to Stilgar.
There.
It's right under
everybody's noses.
Not clever.
That's the idea.
Nobody would ever
look in there
because it's obvious.
Not clever.
Did you find it?
I didn't look for it.
How many heads exactly?
Enough to blow up
the whole planet.
It's a figure of speech.
You know what I mean.
Only with
your genetic heritage.
Your great-great-grandfather's
legacy.
The 92 original Atreides
family's atomic warheads.
Now that. that is power.
Imperial Diary.
year 10.191.
Eighth comment.
Reports from the south
of Arrakis arrive rarely.
These are barren. burnt lands
hidden by sandstorms.
which stretch a thousand miles
across the equator.
Nothing can live there
without faith.
Which is why
our Bene Gesserit missionaries
have been so productive there.
Through them.
we are receiving reports
of a mysterious figure
taking grip
on the imaginations
of the Southern
fundamentalist tribes.
A new Reverend Mother
from the North.
spreading word
of the imminent arrival
of the Lisan al-Gaib.
the Voice
from the Outer World.
With religious fervor rising
in the South.
and Muad'Dib strangling
spice production in the North.
everything points
to the escalation of war.
Hmm.
Quiet.
Listen carefully.
Soon a man is going
to visit your temple
and he may want you
to perform the rites.
Reverend Mother.
it is forbidden.
Let him try.
What the hell?
Chani!
Chani.
Sietch Tabr.
Old fashioned artillery.
Genius.
We're literally melting rock
on their heads.
I want to go on the ground.
Prepare my troops.
My Lord. I would recommend
you stay inside.
There was...
Bring his body to my quarters.
My poor darlings are hungry.
There was no food for them
on the flight.
What are you doing here?
It's early morning.
Kiss my feet. brother.
I'm gonna eviscerate your...
You humiliated our family.
You humiliated me.
Kiss.
or die.
Mm.
We're even now.
Embarrass our family
one more time.
it will be the last.
They didn't
even engage on the ground
like honorable fighters.
Usul.
in the South.
only leaders
are allowed to speak.
You must take my place.
I can't do that.
It is a good time
to cross blades with me.
I am weak.
I am an easy kill. Muad'Dib.
I'd rather cut off
my own hand.
We need you.
We need the Lisan al-Gaib
to lead our people.
You know what I think
of all that. Stilgar.
I don't care what you believe.
I believe.
I didn't see it coming.
The Harkonnens
aren't done here.
They just went back to reload.
We're setting thumpers.
We're moving everyone
to the South.
I'll stay behind
and cover your retreat.
- What are you talking about?
- Chani. I can't go with you.
You know why.
- I'll stay. too.
- Nobody stays but me.
- Paul.
- That's an order.
Gurney Halleck. Go South!
Protect my mother.
- My Lord.
- Muad'Dib.
He's afraid
of the fundamentalists.
And he should be.
Don't resist.
Talk to me. Jamis.
Kwisatz Haderach.
You see only fragments.
You cannot see the future
without seeing the past.
To unlock your mind.
you need to drink
the Water of Life.
and you will see everything.
A good hunter always
climbs the highest dune
before his hunt.
He needs to see...
as far as he can see.
You need to see.
You must drink
the Water of Life.
Your mind. it's gonna open...
...and you will see.
The world has made
choices for us.
If I go South.
I might lose you.
You will never lose me.
Paul Atreides.
Not as long as you stay
who you are.
I'll cross the storms
with you.
Go South.
Bring your people to safety.
And then I will do
what must be done.
Where?
Spy. Left behind.
No trace of the others.
They've gone
South to hide in the storms.
Send this message
to the Baron.
The North is liberated
and secured.
Harvest spice at will.
Yes. na-Baron.
You killed nine of my men
with one single blade.
She won't talk.
Tell her that's fine.
I already know
everything I need to know.
Only pleasure remains.
Now that you can see
our past...
See our past.
you can see your future.
See your future.
My brother.
my dearest brother.
you are not prepared
for what is to come.
You'll now learn the truth
about our family.
And it will hurt you
to the core.
Paul.
don't worry.
I'm with you.
I love you.
Find them.
Paul? Paul.
I'm here. I'm here.
Hey.
What happened?
He's dead.
His vital signs are so low.
they can't be detected.
But he's alive.
What did you do to him?
No. not that.
Why would he do that?
Why would you do that?
Chani. his body
is fighting the poison
and he needs your help.
You do it.
You did this to him.
You did this
to your own son. You do it.
Fix it yourself.
Chani. you might not believe
in the prophecy.
but you're a part of it.
You're the poison.
You and your lies.
- Why would you do this?
- Do it.
Desert Spring tears.
Kwisatz Haderach.
climb up.
Arise.
Usul. I'm here. I'm here.
Are you okay?
Yes.
Are you sure?
Thanks to you.
I'm sorry about Chani.
She'll come to understand.
I've seen it.
You can see?
The visions
are clear now.
I see possible futures.
All at once.
Our enemies are all around us.
And in so many futures.
they prevail.
But I do see a way.
There is a narrow way through.
I saw our bloodline. Mother.
Written across time.
You are the daughter
of Baron Vladimir Harkonnen.
Did my father know?
I didn't know myself.
until I took the worm's poison.
We're Harkonnens.
So this is how we will survive.
By being Harkonnens.
We must talk.
Stilgar. you can stop this.
Do you hear me? You have
the power to stop this.
Northern Woman!
You are not allowed to speak
inside the circle.
If you want to speak.
you know what to do.
Stilgar. please.
For Arrakis' sake.
This prophecy
is how they enslave us!
How they dominate...
You'll get yourself
in trouble.
This is none of your business.
Rabban Harkonnen himself
killed my family.
He gave me this scar
to remember him by.
This is all of my business.
Mahdi. Mahdi.
Only tribe leaders can speak.
If you wish
to share your voice.
you must take his place
by defeating him
and returning his water
to the well.
You think I'm stupid enough
to deprive myself
of the best of us?
Take my life. Usul.
It is the only way.
I'm pointing the way!
Slow down.
But you think
you could have a chance.
Dune.
Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
Mahdi.
Lisan al-Gaib!
- Muad'Dib.
This is
my father's ducal signet.
I am Paul Muad'Dib Atreides.
Duke of Arrakis.
Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
Paul Atreides is still alive.
He challenges my father.
You've never been on Arrakis.
It's quite impressive.
You'll see.
Was this all upon your advice?
What?
Did you counsel my father
to exterminate the Atreides?
Of course I did.
Why else
would it have happened?
You tried to sacrifice
an entire bloodline.
And I was right to do it.
The Kwisatz Haderach
is a form of power
that our world
has not yet seen.
The ultimate power.
For 90 generations.
we have supervised
House Atreides.
They were promising.
but they were becoming
dangerously defiant.
Their bloodline
had to be terminated.
That is why we have put
many bloodlines at work.
Several prospects.
But it's backfired.
Paul is alive.
And if he defeats Feyd-Rautha.
my father...
Your father
will lose the throne.
no matter who prevails.
But there is one way
your family
can remain in power.
and. through you.
the continuation
of our stewardship.
One way.
Are you prepared?
You've been preparing me
my whole life.
Reverend Mother.
You're heading North
with the others?
I'm Fedaykin.
I follow my leaders.
If fighting goes North.
I go North.
Paul didn't have a choice.
Chani.
I won't be fighting for him.
I'm fighting for my people.
I came to wish you
best of luck.
I'd wish you the same...
but it seems
you've won your battle.
He took the bait.
Well.
the Emperor's very obliging.
He's right on time.
What is he doing here?
I brought spice production
under control.
What do we do?
Send messages
to the Great Houses.
Tell them that Arrakis
is under Sardaukar attack.
Tell them. their future hangs
in the balance.
When the storm hits this ridge.
Gurney will open the way
for you. Stilgar.
so you can enter the basin
from the West
and distract
their defense systems.
Chani. I want
you and your Fedaykin
to then attack from the East.
inside the basin.
I'll strike from the North.
head on.
with the Fundamentalist
troops.
And I'll serve Arrakeen
for dessert.
Remember.
I need the Emperor alive.
Hmm.
Baron.
do you have any idea
who this Muad'Dib could be?
Some fanatic. Your Majesty.
- That's all we know.
- More. More.
- Give me more.
- He's a madman.
- Mad?
- All Fremen are mad.
That's all you know?
Really?
Muad'Dib is dead.
Or. he went hiding
in the southern storms.
which means the same thing.
Your Majesty.
the sandstorm
that's approaching
threatens the integrity
of our shields.
We recommend
going back into orbit.
Well. the mountains will
protect us from most of it.
Your Majesty.
Baron. have you
ever investigated
the south regions of Arrakis?
Well. the entire region
is uninhabitable.
It's well known. your Majesty.
Your uninhabited South
exhibits evidence
of human activity.
I wasn't aware of this.
I swear to you.
I wasn't aware of any of this.
Muad'Dib is alive.
I must find him.
Fire!
Sardaukar!
On guard!
Grandfather.
You die like an animal.
Muad'Dib.
Oh. Muad'Dib!
Muad'Dib! Muad'Dib! Muad'Dib!
Rabban!
Look who's back
from the dead.
For my Duke. and my friends.
Warships.
The Great Houses.
Gurney. it's time.
Bring the prisoners.
My Lord.
This isn't over yet.
I want you to know...
I will love you
as long as I breathe.
There is a massed armada
in orbit.
You're facing a full invasion.
Fremen.
How can you be so sure
the Great Houses
are here for me?
They may be curious
to hear my side of the story.
don't you think?
I am Paul Atreides.
son of Leto Atreides.
Duke of Arrakis.
- Gurney.
- My Lord.
Send a warning
to all ships.
If the Great Houses attack.
our atomics will obliterate
all spice fields.
You're out of your mind.
He's bluffing.
Consider what you're about
to do. Paul Atreides.
Silence!
Abomination.
Message sent. my Lord.
As a servant of the Imperium.
you will bow at my feet.
Your feet?
You'll be lucky
to keep your head.
I'll take the hand
of your daughter.
She will remain safe.
And we will rule together
over the Empire.
But you...
You have to answer
for my father.
Do you know why
I killed him?
Because he was a man
who believed
in the rules of the heart.
But the heart
is not meant to rule.
In other words...
your father
was a weak man.
Stand
or choose your champion.
I am here. Atreides.
I need a blade.
Accept mine.
Do not stain your hands
on this animal.
Let me deal with him.
It's my burden. Gurney.
Why does he take such risks?
Muad'Dib leads the way.
I'm happy to finally meet you.
cousin.
Cousin?
Is that right?
Well.
you wouldn't be the first
relative I've killed.
May thy knife chip
and shatter.
She's your pet?
Any special attention
for the pet?
You fought well. Atreides.
- Lisan al-Gaib.
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
You should have believed.
You chose the wrong side.
Side?
You. of all people.
should know.
There are no sides.
Reverend Mother.
The life debt has been paid.
Spare my father now
and I will be
your willing bride.
The throne will be yours.
My Lord.
the Great Houses
have answered.
They refuse to honor
your ascendancy.
We await your orders.
Lisan al-Gaib.
- Lead them to Paradise.
- Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
What is happening. Mother?
Your brother attacks
the Great Houses.
The Holy War begins.